你真的做了一些
you've done some really
在最后两个部分努力创造
hard work in the last two sections to create
服务器进程
a server process
有状态的
that has state
并且确实异步工作
and does work asynchronously
所有这些工作都将得到回报
and all that work is about to pay off
因为 elixir 有一个抽象
because elixir has an abstraction
用于编写服务器进程并相信与否
for writing server processes and believe it or not
你现在知道它是如何工作的
you now know how it works
抽象被称为等待它
the abstraction is called wait for it
生成服务器
gen server
所以在一分钟内我们将摆脱所有这些代码
so in a minute we're going to get rid of all this code
并将其替换为性别模块
and replace it with the gendered module
但在我们离开这段代码之前
but before we move away from this code
注意它封装了冷静和服务器行为
notice it encapsulates calm and server behavior
并委托回调函数
and delegates to call back functions
运行特定于进程的代码
to run code that specific to a process
因此，它强制执行隐含合同
as such it enforces an implicit contract
回调
the callback
模块必须实现某些回调函数
module must implement certain callback functions
处理调用和处理转换
handle call and handle cast
所以这段代码实现了一个设计
so this code implements a design
spadeful 服务器进程的模式
pattern for spadeful server processes
在顶部设计
in top a design
像这样的模式被称为行为
pattern like this is referred to as a behavior
gen server 是一种行为
gen server is a behavior
用于编写大量的服务器进程
for writing spadeful server processes
它包含在顶级库中
it's included in the top libraries
顶部包括封装的其他行为
top includes other behaviors that encapsulate
设计模式
design patterns for
其他流程，例如主管
other processes such as supervisors
稍后会了解
which will learn about a bit later
现在可能不足为奇
now probably doesn't come as a surprise
给您从我们的通用服务器转换
to you that converting from our generic server
到 gen 服务器模块
to the gen server module
将会变得非常简单
is going to turn out to be pretty straightforward
在很大程度上
in large part
因为我们遵循 gen server 命名约定
because we follow the gen server naming conventions
但在我们这样做之前
but before we do that
您可能想要保存此代码的一个版本
you might want to save off a version of this code
只为你
just for your
参考
reference
一种方法是复制此文件
one way to do that would be to duplicate this file
例如，我们可以将其称为质押服务器手卷
we could call it pledge server hand rolled for example
然后在这里我们需要改变
then down here we need to change
要匹配的此模块的名称
the name of this module to match
所以我会得到所有这些事件
so I'll just get all those occurrences
并将它们更改为质押服务器手卷
and change them to pledge server hand rolled
然后我要注释掉
then I'm going to comment out
模块之外的所有代码
all the code that's outside of the module
因为我们不想要这个
because we don't want this
当我们启动性行为时运行的代码
code running when we fire up sex
最后我们需要更改注册名称
and finally we need to change the registered name
我们在这里有这个名字
we've got this at name up here
我们不希望这成为质押服务器
we don't want this to be pledge server
因为我们只能拥有
because we can only have
一个以给定名称注册的进程
one process registered under a given name
所以我要把它改成质押服务器
so I'm going to change this to pledge server
手卷并重命名所有这些东西
hand rolled and by renaming all this stuff
我们不会以任何命名冲突告终
we won't end up with any naming collisions
与东西
with the things
我们将回到质押服务器
that we're going to have back in pledge server
现在是转换的第一步
now the first step to converting
从我们的通用服务器到 gen 服务器
from our generic server to a gen server
我们喜欢这一步
and we love this step
是彻底删除通用服务器
is to completely remove the generic server
性别模块照顾所有
the gendered module takes care of all
这些通用细节对我们来说
of these generic details for us
还有更多
and a whole lot more
那么我们可以摆脱这个
then we can get rid of this
别名，因为我们不再有通用服务器
alias because we don't have a generic server anymore
然后在这里我们称之为通用服务器的任何地方
and then everywhere we call generic server here
所有这些事件
all these occurrences
这只是一个 gen server
this is just going to be gen server
那是顶级库中的模块
that's the module that's in the top libraries
现在我们在 gen server 模块上调用 start
now we're calling start on the gen server module
和你的方式
and the way you
为 gen 服务器设置名称是第三个参数
set a name for a gen server is the third argument
需要是关键字列表，所以这些是选项
needs to be a keyword list so these are options
我们会说名字是在名字
we're going to say the name is going to be at name
这将以该名称注册进程
and that'll register the process under that name
现在不像我们手卷的通用服务器模块
now unlike our hand rolled generic server module
gen 服务器模块需要回调模块
the gen server module expects the callback module
实现六个回调函数
to implement six callback functions
因为我们遵循了 gen 服务器命名约定
since we followed the gen server naming conventions
已定义的 pled 服务器模块
the pled server module already defined
六个必需的回调函数中的两个
two of the six required callback functions
处理调用和处理转换
handle call and handle cast
现在我们不需要其他四个
now we don't need the other four
还需要回调函数
required callback functions just yet
我们稍后再看
we'll look at those a bit later
并且经常
and oftentimes
你根本不需要其他四个功能
you don't need the other four functions at all
所以不必实现所有
so instead of having to implement all
六个回调函数
six callback functions
履行我们的讨价还价
to fulfill our side of the bargain
我们可以让性别模块
we can let the gendered module
为我们生成默认实现
generate default implementations for us
我们可以通过转到文件顶部来做到这一点
and we can do that by going to the top of the file
并添加一行
and adding one line
使用 g
use g
使用宏
the use macro
注入回调模块的默认实现
injects default implementations of the callback modules
进入我们的质押服务器模块
into our pledge server module
我们已经定义了句柄调用和句柄转换
we've already defined handle call and handle cast which
覆盖
override
这些回调函数的默认实现
the default implementation of these callback functions
但我们需要非常改变它们
but we need to change them very
稍微符合 gen server 的期望
slightly to conform to what gen server expects
是的，手柄演员需要返回状态
yeah handle cast needs to return the state
包裹在一个元组中
wrapped in a tuple
该元组的第一个元素是原子
and the first element of that tuple is the atom
无回复
no reply
然后第二个元素就是新状态
and then the second element is just the new state
和其他原子是
and other atoms are
可以在这里
possible here
但到目前为止，没有任何回复是您最常使用的回复
but no reply is by far the one you'll use the most
我们的句柄调用函数已经返回元组
our handle call functions already return to tuple
但他们需要
but they need to be
用第一个元素标记为回复
tagged with the first element being reply
就这样
just like that
所以我们把它放在这里
so we'll put that down here
也在这里
and down here as well
回复
reply
表示服务器应该回复客户端
indicates that the server should reply to the client
它将向它发送此值的第二个元素
it's going to send it the second element this value
然后第三个元素是新状态
and then the third element is the new state
我们需要再做一个改变
we need to make one more change
到这些句柄调用函数子句
to these handle call function clauses
他们目前采取
they currently take
两个论点，但性别要求他们采取
two arguments but gendered requires them to take
三个论点
three arguments
第二个参数是一些信息
the second argument is some information
关于我要打电话的发件人
about the sender I'm going to call it from
但通常不需要
but it's typically not needed
所以我们将忽略它，我们将使用下划线
so we'll just ignore it we'll use underscore from
所以这是第二个论点，我们也会把它放在这里
so that's the second argument we'll put it here as well
最后在这里
and finally down here
我们需要做的最后一个改变是关闭
the last change we need to make is down
在这里我们启动服务器
here where we start the server
现在在左侧我们只匹配一个 pid
right now on the left hand side we just match a pid
但请记住质押服务器启动
but remember that pledge server start
调用 gen server start
calls gen server start
它返回一个元组而不仅仅是一个pid
and it returns a tuple rather than just a pid
元组有一个原子
the tuple has an atom okay
然后pid只是第二个元素
and then the pid is just a second element
所以现在我们的 pled 服务器满足了所有
so now our pled server fulfills all
生成服务器的要求
the requirements of a gen server
所以它应该工作
so it should work
我们把它存起来
we save it away
果然如此
and sure enough it does ya
所以当你在模块中看到这条用过的线时
so when you see this used line in a module
你马上就知道
you know right away
这是一个服务器进程
that it's a server process that
至少这是一个基本水平
at least that a fundamental level
行为与所有其他 gen 服务器进程一样
behaves like all other gen server processes
现在我们已经转换为使用 gen 服务器
now that we've converted over to use a gen server
让我们介绍一条新消息
let's introduce a new message
只是为了走过台阶
just to walk through the steps
我们的现金目前持有三项认捐
our cash currently holds three pledges
但是让我们假设我们希望能够改变
but let's suppose we want to be able to change
服务器运行良好时的现金规模
the cash size while the server is running well
因为我们不能努力
since we can't hard
编码大小
code the size
它需要成为服务器状态的一部分
it'll need to be part of the server state
所以国家将包括承诺清单和
so the state will include the list of pledges and
代表现金规模的数字
a number representing the cash size
这意味着当我们启动服务器时
which means when we start the server
传递一个空列表是不够的
passing an empty list won't be enough
好吧，我们可以给它一张地图
well we could pass it a map
该地图将有一个现金大小的钥匙
the map would have a cash size key
是默认值三
was that default value of three
然后它会有我们的承诺，这是一个清单
and then it would have our pledges which is a list
那会奏效
and that would work
但是如果我们有更多的状态，它就会变得笨拙
but it gets unwieldy if we have even more state
所以我们想向您展示另一种技术
so we want to show you another technique
随着国家越来越多地参与
as the state gets more involved
定义一个结构很方便
it's handy to define a structure with
具有默认值的字段
fields having default values
所以让我们这样做
so let's do that
我们将把我们的
we're going to put our s
就在我们的质押服务器模块内部
right inside of our pledge server module
所以这个结构将被称为状态
so the structure is going to be called state
def 被击中，然后它将有两个字段
def struck and then it's going to have two fields
铸件尺寸和承诺
cast size and pledges
这些将是默认值
and those are going to be the default values
然后我们可以改变我们的启动功能
then we can change our start function
使用该初始状态
to use that initial state
就这样
just like that
现在我们需要
now we need to
改变我们的回调函数
change our callback functions since
他们假设国家
they assume that the state
只是一个承诺清单
is just a list of pledges
所以在我们清晰的演员阵容中
so down in our clear cast right here
我们需要改变这个状态
we're going to need to change this state
所以我要删除那里的下划线
so I'm going to remove the underscore there
因为我要在这里改变它
because I'm going to change it here
我们只想设置这个的承诺字段
and we just want to set the pledges field of this
击中一个空列表
struck to an empty list
为了做到这一点，我们像这样说状态
and to do that we go like this we say state
记住这是一个结构，我们要修改
remember that's a structure and we want to modify
承诺字段并将其设置为空列表
the pledges field and set it to an empty list
所以这将返回一个新结构
so this will return a new structure
具有当前演员阵容的
that has the current cast size
但承诺字段更改为空列表
but the pledges field is changed to an empty list
现在就这里承诺的总额而言
now in terms of this total pledged here
我们想要映射到状态而不是映射到状态
instead of mapping on state we want to map on state
承诺，因为我们正在总结
pledges because we're summing up
认捐清单总数
the total of the pledges list
然后出于原因承诺
and then for reason pledges
好吧，我们想与国家再次发生
well we want to recurs with the state
但我们想回来
but we want to return
国家承诺回馈给客户
state pledges back to the client
好的，现在开始创建承诺
okay now on to create pledge
好吧，而不是从国家那里拿走
well instead of taking from the state
我们需要从国家承诺中获取
we need to take from state pledges
而不是硬编码第二个
and instead of hard coding the number two
这将是国家现金规模
this is going to be state cash size
然后我们要减去一个
and then we're going to subtract one
因为记得
because remember
我们要添加
we're going to add
对名单首领的新承诺
the new pledge to the head of that list
但这里的问题是
but the problem here is this
不是我们想要返回的新状态
isn't the new state that we want to return
这实际上是现在的现金承诺
this is actually the cash pledges now
新状态
the new state
是当前状态
is the current state
承诺更改为新的演员承诺的地方
where the pledges gets changed to the new cast pledges
然后我们接受它并重复它
and then we take that and we recurs with it
所以在我们运行之前
so before we run this
让我们重新排列我们的代码
let's go down and rearrange our code
我们会在拉里之后打电话给clear
we'll call clear after larry
现在当我们运行它时
and now when we run it
好吧，我们应该看到最近的三个承诺
well we should see the three most recent pledges
因为毕竟
because after all
这是默认的现金大小
that's the default cash size
但是现在如果我们想要现金规模怎么办
but now what if we want the cash size to be for
好
well
首先我们需要实现一个客户端接口函数
first we need to implement a client interface function
所以我们称之为设定现金规模
so let's call it set cash size
是的，我们希望能够这样称呼它
yeah we want to be able to call it like this
领导服务器
led server
设置现金大小
set cash size
传球4号
passing in a No.4
所以让我们继续执行它
so let's go ahead and implement that
在我们的客户端界面函数中
up in our client interface functions
它需要一个尺寸
it's going to take a size
好的，所以这应该是电话还是演员信息
okay so should this be a call or a cast message
嗯，这真的是一个设计决定
well this is really a design decision
在这种情况下，客户实际上并不需要响应
in this case the client doesn't really need a response
它可以假设请求是成功的
it can assume the request was successful
如果由于某种原因失败，这并不重要
and it's not critical if for some reason it fails
所以我们会把它变成演员表
so we'll make it a cast
所以它是有性别的
so it's gendered
cast at name 并且消息将设置为 cast size
cast at name and the message will be set cast size
和大小
and the size
所以现在我们需要使用爪子来处理该消息
so now we need to function claws to handle that message
这将是一个演员
and it's going to be a cast
所以我们要把它做对
so we're going to put it right
在这个现有的手柄铸件下方
below this existing handle cast
因为我们想把这些放在一起
because we want to keep these together
所有手柄铸件
all the handle casts
并且所有的句柄调用都组合在一起
and all the handle calls get grouped together
所以处理演员表
so handle cast
消息
the message
设置现金大小大小
set cash size size
然后它也需要状态
and then it also takes the state
然后是新状态
and then the new state
将是现有状态
will be the existing state
但我们想改变现金大小
but we want to change the cash size
任何传入的东西
to whatever gets passed in
然后我们需要返回两个极点
and then we need to return the two pole
没有回复，因为这是演员阵容和新状态
no reply because this is the cast and the new state
现在如果我们保存它并运行它
and now if we save this away and we run it
好吧，现在我们的现金有四个承诺，而不是三个
well now our cash has four pledges instead of three
我们之前说过，当你添加
we said earlier that when you add
使用 gen server 到一个模块
use gen server to a module
六个默认回调被注入到该模块中
six default callbacks are injected into that module
然后您添加应用程序特定的行为
you then add application specific behavior
通过覆盖任何默认实现
by overriding any of the default implementations
到目前为止，我们已经覆盖了两个回调
we've overridden two callbacks so far
处理调用和处理转换
handle call and handle cast
所以现在让我们看看另外两个最常见的
so now let's look at two of the other most frequently
被覆盖的回调
overridden callbacks
目前当我们初始化我们的服务器
currently when we initialize our server
我们使用默认状态
we use the default state
所以当我们开始这个过程时，承诺清单是
so when we start the process the pledge list is
理想情况下总是空的
always empty ideally
当我们开始这个过程
when we start the process
它会去拿最多的
it would go and fetch the most
外部服务部门最近的认捐
recent pledges from the external service
然后准备填充我们的内存现金
and then prep populate our in memory cash
这就是 nit 回调进来的地方
and that's where the nit call back comes in
这是该回调的默认实现
here's the default implementation of that callback
我要把它放下
and I'm going to put it down
在服务器回调下
under server callbacks
它看起来像这样并编织
it looks like this and knit
它需要 rag 然后返回元组 ok 和 rag
it takes rag and then returns the tuple ok and rag
所以当我们在这里调用启动时会发生什么
so what happens is when we call start up here
这个第二个参数状态变成了
this 2nd argument state becomes the value that's
传递到 knit 中会自动调用 knit
passed into a knit a knit is automatically called
它通过了第二个参数
it passes in that 2nd argument
这将是这里的值
which is going to be a value of a here
然后默认实现就转过来了
and then the default implementation just turns around
并在元组中返回拖动
and returns drag in a tuple
所以在我们的例子中认为是状态
so in our case argues is the state
所以让我们把它改成状态
so let's just change that to state
只是为了更清楚
just to make it more clear
然后因为状态在这个元组中返回
and then because state is returned in this tuple
该状态将得到
that state will get
用于在服务器启动时初始化服务器
used to initialize the server when it starts
所以默认情况下它只是通过状态
so by default it just passes the state through
这是不行的
it's a no up
但是我们可以覆盖它来做我们想做的任何事情
but we can override it to do whatever we want
所以我们想要做的是填充我们的现金
so what we want to do is are populate our cash
好吧，我们在这里添加了一个功能
well we added a function down here
从服务中获取最近的承诺
fetch recent pledges from service
所以你会在这里放一些代码来实际运行
so you'd put some code here to actually go
从外部服务获取最近的承诺
fetch the recent pledges from the external service
我们不会担心的
and we're not going to worry about that
然后它将转换返回的任何内容
and then it would convert whatever got returned
进入元组列表
into a list of tuples
我们的性别期望然后我们返回那个
that our gendered expects and then we just return that
所以你可以想象威尔玛和弗雷德
so you can imagine wilma and fred
成为最
being the most
我们的外部服务返回的近期承诺
recent pledges returned by our external service
现在在我们的 knit 回调中备份
now back up in our knit callback
让我们继续使用它来准备填充现金
let's go ahead and use that to prep populate the cash
所以我们会说承诺
so we'll say pledges
等于从服务中获取最近的承诺
equals fetch recent pledges from service
好的，现在我们要更新这个状态，因为记住
okay now we want to update this state because remember
这是默认状态
this is the default state
具有空承诺列表的结构
structure which has an empty list of pledges
所以新的状态
so the new state
将是现有状态
is going to be the existing state
更新承诺字段的位置
where the pledges field is updated
成为该外部服务返回的任何东西
to be whatever got returned by that external service
然后我们只需要确保改变这个
and then we just need to make sure to change this
到新状态
to new state
所以只是回顾一下这里发生的事情
so just to recap what happens here
当调用 start 来启动我们的服务器时
when start is called to start our server
这第二个参数将被传递给 knit
this 2nd argument is going to get passed to a knit
并且 knit 会被 gen 自动调用
and knit's going to be automatically called by gen
服务器
server
所以 state 将成为我们 state 的默认结构
so state is going to be the default structure our state
然后我们要更新那个状态
then we want to update that state
我们从服务中获取承诺
we go fetch the pledges from the service
更新状态以拥有
update the state to have
认捐领域的那些认捐
those pledges in the pledges field
这成为我们返回的新状态
that becomes the new state which we return
并且 gen server 使用这个值 new state
and gen server uses this value new state
在服务器启动时初始化服务器
to initialize the server when it starts
现在在我们运行这个之前，让我们深入到底部
now before we run this let's go down to the bottom
让我们注释清楚
and let's comment out clear
和拉里之后的所有承诺
and all the pledges after larry
所以现在当我们运行它时
so now when we run it
我们看到服务器启动
we see that the server starts the
用外部服务的两项认捐兑现
cash with the two pledges from the external service
然后加上拉里的保证
and then adds on larry's pledge
现在有一个警告
now there's one caveat to this
重要的是要注意
it's important to note that
开始会阻止并告诉这个
start will block and tell this
一个 knit 函数返回
a knit function returns
所以请注意初始化需要多长时间
so just be mindful of how long initialization takes
让我们再下一次
let's go down to the bottom one more time
因为我注意到这条线
because I noticed that the line
我们发送意外消息的地方
where we send an unexpected message
评论了
it's commented
所以让我们不寻常
so let's uncommon
现在运行它
and now run it
看看现在我们在性别化的土地上会发生什么
and see what happens now that we're in gendered land
哦，我们得到一个错误
ooo we get an error
注意它说的是质押服务器
notice it says the pledge server
在句柄信息中收到意外消息
received an unexpected message in handle info
现实二
of reality two
然后它显示出意外的消息
and then it shows the unexpected message
在姜地时
while in ginger land
句柄信息是一个回调函数
handle info is a callback function
自动调用来处理
that's automatically called to handle
任何未使用 call 或 cast 发送的消息
any messages that aren't sent using call or cast
并且发送了我们意想不到的消息
and our unexpected message was sent
直接使用发送功能
directly using the send function
有点像自发的消息
kind of like a message that came spontaneously
出乎意料
out of the blue
当这种情况发生时
and when that happens
调用句柄信息回调
the handle info callback is called
带着那条信息
with that message
现在默认实现只是
now the default implementation just
记录我们在这里看到的空气
logs the air as we saw right here
但是我们可以覆盖回调来做我们自己的事情
but we can override the callback to do our own thing
好吧，我们就上这里
all right we'll go up here
我们将把它放在句柄调用下
we're going to put it under handle call
回调是句柄信息
the callback is handle info
我们知道这是永恒的二
we know it's an eternity two
第一件事是消息
the first thing is the message
第二件事是国家
the second thing is the state
然后我们就打印出来
and then we'll just print out
不能碰这个
can't touch this
然后我们将检查消息
and then we'll inspect the message
然后它需要返回一个元组
then it needs to return a tuple
第一个元素是原子没有回复
the first element is the atom no reply
第二个元素是状态
and the second element is the state
如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
if we save that away and run it
而现在我们看到了实现的输出
while now that we see the output of our implementation
现在这个例子有点做作，我们会给你
now this example is a bit contrived we'll give you that
但事实证明
but it turns out
处理信息有很多实际用途
handle info has many practical uses
除了处理意外消息
beyond handling unexpected messages
我们将看到一个更实际的句柄信息示例
we'll see a more practical example of the handle info
下一节回调
callback in the next section
我们开始用手滚动铲子
we started by hand rolling a spadeful
server 进程，然后我们将其转换为 gen server
server process and then we converted it to a gen server
所以你会有更好的
so you'd have a better
了解引擎盖下发生的事情
idea of what goes on under the hood
它不再神奇
it's no longer magical
所以当你去编写自己的服务器进程时
so when you go to write your own server process
我们强烈建议使用 gen server
we strongly recommend using gen server
马上
right off the bat
而不是自己滚动
rather than rolling your own
jen 服务器在许多方面都经过了艰苦的战斗
jen server has been battle hardened over many
在生产环境中使用多年
years of use in production environments
所有粗糙的边缘空气处理
all the rough edges air handling
类似的微妙角落案例已被平滑处理
subtle corner cases in the like have been smoothed off
jen 服务器包含许多生产就绪功能
and jen server includes many production ready features
我们甚至没有触及
we didn't even touch on
用它
use it
你会站在巨人的肩膀上
and you'll be standing on the shoulders of giants